<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kunal Sumbly</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kunal Sumbly</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>kunal.sumbly@gmail.com (Kunal Sumbly)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>kunal.sumbly@gmail.com (Kunal Sumbly)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2021 Kunal Sumbly.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 22:29:18 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Host Personal Website/Blog on AWS S3 using Hugo</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-host-hugo-static-website-s3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 22:29:18 +1100</pubDate>
      <author>kunal.sumbly@gmail.com (Kunal Sumbly)</author>
      <guid>/post/how-to-host-hugo-static-website-s3/</guid>
      <description>Problem statement In this tutorial we will be hosting a static website on AWS S3 bucket. The website domain will be registered on AWS Route53 which in AWS world acts both the Domain registrar and DNS provider. Also we would be using another AWS service called CloudFront that is similar to Akamai and acts as a CDN (Content Delivery Network) which in layman&amp;rsquo;s terms means a blazing fast cache to store static content closer to the user&amp;rsquo;s geographical location.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLI Testing in Go</title>
      <link>/post/cli-testing-golang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2016 08:19:39 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>kunal.sumbly@gmail.com (Kunal Sumbly)</author>
      <guid>/post/cli-testing-golang/</guid>
      <description>Writing unit tests for Go (Golang) CLIs A majority of my background has been developing web applications. I&amp;rsquo;ve recently changed teams at work to a team that is primarily focused on building a CLI.
Writing tests in Go is a relatively simple process, especially coming from JavaScript where you need multiple modules, and lots of code before you even begin writing tests.
The testing package has most everything you need for writing unit tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bestrida</title>
      <link>/post/bestrida/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2016 09:45:50 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>kunal.sumbly@gmail.com (Kunal Sumbly)</author>
      <guid>/post/bestrida/</guid>
      <description>I recently published Bestrida to the iOS app store for my submission to the 2016 Strava Developer Challenge. Here is a brief overview of the application. Strava.com is a popular and widely used website and mobile app that over one million cyclists and runners use to track their activity via GPS. Whenever you go for a run or ride your bike, Strava will track and store your activity and provide you with useful statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>kunal.sumbly@gmail.com (Kunal Sumbly)</author>
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Kunal Sumbly.
Senior Software Engineer with 11+ years in banking and financial services industry. Experienced in implementing Enterprise Software Products. Customer-centric with expertise in customer-facing roles, working closely with clients from the inception of the project, through high-level and detailed design/implementation to launch and post-go-live support.
Passionate about technology, proficient in different technical stacks in the Java Ecosystem, Cloud Computing , AWS and DevOps.
Follow me on Github and Twitter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
