<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GIS on Kunal Sumbly</title>
    <link>/tags/gis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GIS on Kunal Sumbly</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>kunal.sumbly@gmail.com (Kunal Sumbly)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>kunal.sumbly@gmail.com (Kunal Sumbly)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2021 Kunal Sumbly.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 10:29:42 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/gis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Installing PostGIS and QGIS using Homebrew</title>
      <link>/post/installing-postgis-and-qgis-using-homebrew/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 10:29:42 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>kunal.sumbly@gmail.com (Kunal Sumbly)</author>
      <guid>/post/installing-postgis-and-qgis-using-homebrew/</guid>
      <description>After browsing the web and seeing outdated information for installing GIS software, I wanted to document the steps I took to install all the required software to get up and running using Homebrew:
Installing Homebrew Be sure to have xcode installed from Apple
xcode-select --installCopy this code a paste into your terminal to download and install Homebrew:
ruby -e &amp;quot;$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Homebrew/install/master/install)&amp;quot;Installing PostGIS First, using Homebrew install PostgreSQL:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating Feature Coordinates With Python</title>
      <link>/post/updating-feature-coordinates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2015 08:45:13 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>kunal.sumbly@gmail.com (Kunal Sumbly)</author>
      <guid>/post/updating-feature-coordinates/</guid>
      <description>I was asked to update the location of manhole points with new survey data. Traditionally this is a long task, dragging the old manholes to their new locations.
Before we assume how it would be so much easier to just delete the old data, and import the new data. First we have to consider all the attribute information associated with the data, sure we can join based on the Manhole ID but what happens when we have to worry about attachments?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributing to Turf.js</title>
      <link>/post/turf-js/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 08:51:45 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>kunal.sumbly@gmail.com (Kunal Sumbly)</author>
      <guid>/post/turf-js/</guid>
      <description>Over the winter I was able to spend some free time assisting with the development of the Turf.js project!
This was a very rewarding experience that has allowed me to better grasp some very important topics:
Test Driven Development Test driven development is one of the most powerful concepts I picked up while working with Turf. Turf uses the Tape testing environment, and just like turf, focuses on being lightweight and fast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Map Service Usage</title>
      <link>/post/visualizing-map-service-usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2013 08:41:16 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>kunal.sumbly@gmail.com (Kunal Sumbly)</author>
      <guid>/post/visualizing-map-service-usage/</guid>
      <description>I recently developed a JavaScript web application to visualize incident reporting for a local municipality collecting Stormwater Incident Reports.
The idea behind this application, will be to determine the usage of the reporting system, and to additionally determine &amp;ldquo;Problem Areas&amp;rdquo; for further corrective action planning.
Importance of Dynamic Display One of the most important considerations for determining areas, is to determine the scale. The scale the data is viewed at can change the data is interpreted.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
